## **ALADE STEPHEN**

# **Programmer**

2, Jegede Street Ifako Gbagada, Lagos Nigeria Tel: +2347034952654

Email: soalade@outlook.com | Skype: soalade

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Experienced in creating secure and functional code, providing quality coding solutions both for simple applications and complex information, designing and building superior and innovative software by writing clean and flawless code. Competent at transforming software designs and specifications into high functioning code in the appropriate language, integrating individual software solutions to higher level systems, and using web-based tools to create advanced SaaS.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Web Application Development
- IT Project Management
- Database Management
- IT Infrastructure Procurement
- Application Workflow Design
- Training and Development
- Business Intelligence
- Team Leadership

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

- Development of MakeupLyza using Typescript, Angular2 and Cordova; 2017
- Service Desk Plus IT Vendor and Issue Management application; 2017
- Integration with Ameyo Call Center application Service; 2016
- Computer Vision Open CV and Raspberry Pi; 2016
- E-Health (Java Web app Deployed on Heroku); 2016

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **NLPC PFA, Lagos**

Programmer I; August 2015 – Date

- Managing the corporate Website using ASP MVC and entity framework
- Developed an E-Pension Solution database Schema and application workflow design
- Generating transaction reports for client data clean up (SQL Server) and E-Statement
- Preparing executive proposals for IT infrastructure procurement and minutes of departmental meeting

#### **Longbridge Technologies, Lagos**

Software Engineer; June 2015 – August 2015

- Developed the payment integration module for ADH merchant house using play framework
- Ensued REST (JAX/WS) web service integration with NIBSS payment gateway
- Managed Stress test on the web service/payment (Trade finance) module using Apache JMeter

#### HiiT, Lagos

#### Software Developer/Resource Person; August 2014–2015

- Trained students on the use of Java and J2EE applications
- Coached Students on the web and scripting technologies(HTML, CSS and JavaScript)
- Facilitated the use of server side and database languages(PHP and MYSQL)

#### 3Consulting, Lagos

Technical Consultant; August 2013 - August 2014

- Developing proof of concepts for (J2EE, JSF Primefaces)
- Managing Oracle WebLogic 11g webserver
- Preparing application development reports

## **EDUCATION**

- B. Tech. Computer Science, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomosho; 2011
- NIIT, Lagos; 2005
  Windows Operating System Installation and Configuration, Microsoft Office Packages, HTML, CSS and JavaScript, Java, Linux Fundamentals
- OCA WebLogic Certified, DEVINIM; 2013

  Re-Installation & Configuration of WebLogic, deploying applications using JDeveloper